[jaunty nautical music]
[欢快的航海音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Now remember, boyo,
I'm trusting you
现在记住，男孩，
我信任你
to take care of me house
when I'm away.
照顾我的家
当我不在的时候。
House sitting is a very
important responsibility.
坐屋是一件很
重要的责任。
Check the windows,
检查窗户，
and make sure
the security system
并确保
安全系统
is always on your person.
总是在你身上。
Ooh!
哦！
[bat whooshing]
[蝙蝠呼啸]
Yow!
- Whoa!
哟！
- 哇！
- [goofy babbling]
- [gasps]
- [愚蠢的胡言乱语]
- [喘气]
Scratch that last order.
取消最后一个订单。
And do not step foot
into me bedroom!
并且不要踩脚
进我卧室！
I've got me private things
in there.
我有我私人的东西
在那里。
[giggles, clears throat]
[咯咯笑，清清喉咙]
Now, Pearl is staying
with friends,
现在，珍珠留下来了
和朋友一起，
so you'll be here all alone.
所以你会独自一人在这里。
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs,
别担心，蟹老板，
your house is in
good hands with me.
你的房子在
和我一起好手。
Hmm.
唔。
[sneezes]
Huh, huh?
[打喷嚏]
嗯，嗯？
See?
[laughing]
看？
[笑]
[sighs]
[叹气]
Now, there's been
a rash of robberies
现在，已经有
一系列的抢劫
in the neighborhood,
在附近，
so do not open the door...
所以不要开门...
[drawn out]
For anyone!
[拉出来]
对于任何人！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[sighs, laughs]
[叹气，笑]
[knocking on door]
[敲门]
[hums]
[哼哼]
I told you not to open the door
我告诉过你不要开门
for anyone!
对于任何人！
Yes, sir![grunts]
是的，先生！[咕哝]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Uh, I think the boy's got it.
呃，我想这孩子已经明白了。
[weak laugh]
[虚弱的笑声]
Hmm...
[exclaims softly]
嗯...
[轻声喊道]
Huh?
[goofy exclamations]
啊？
[愚蠢的感叹]
Hmm.
唔。
[toilet flushes]
[厕所冲水]
[goofy exclamations]
[愚蠢的感叹]
I checked everywhere
and no sign of robber... huh?
我到处检查了
没有强盗的迹象...嗯？
Huh, Mr. Krabs' bedroom.
嗯，蟹老板的卧室。
I don't remember
his door being ajar.
我不记得了
他的门半开着。
There could be robbers in there.
里面可能有强盗。
Do not step foot
into me bedroom!
请勿踩脚
进我卧室！
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs,
别担心，蟹老板，
I won't "step foot"
in your bedroom.
我不会“迈出一步”
在你的卧室里。
[laughs]
[goofy exclamations]
[笑]
[愚蠢的感叹]
[curious music]
[好奇的音乐]
Seems pretty clear of robbers.
看来劫匪的踪迹还算清楚。
[sniffs, giggles]
Smells like Mr. Krabs.
[嗅嗅，咯咯笑]
闻起来像蟹老板。
Ooh, no wonder!
[laughs]
哦，难怪！
[笑]
Hmm.
[humming]
唔。
[嗡嗡声]
Better check in here too.
最好也在这里检查一下。
[dainty tune playing]
[优美的曲子演奏]
Aww, so Puffy.
哇哦，太蓬松了。
Huh?
Ooh, "Midnight Pincer."
啊？
哦，“午夜钳子”。
[eagle screams]
[singer yodeling]
[鹰的尖叫声]
[歌手约德尔调]
♪ ♪
♪♪
It's a very romantic-er-er
evening, Mrs. Puff.
这是一个非常浪漫的呃呃
晚上好，普夫太太。
[imitating Mr. Krabs' laugh]
[模仿蟹老板的笑声]
[exclaims]
Hmm.
[惊呼]
嗯。
[laughs]
Nighty-night, Mrs. Puff.
[笑]
晚安，普夫太太。
[goofy grunting]
[愚蠢的咕哝]
Wow, look at Mr. Krabs'
knot collection.
哇，看看蟹老板的
结集合。
Ooh, that dingle dangle
should "knot" be there.
哦，那个叮叮当当的晃来晃去
应该有“结”。
[laughs]
♪ La-la-la ♪
[笑]
♪ 啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
[goofy babbling]
Huh?
[胡言乱语]
啊？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[goofy babbling]
[胡言乱语]
Ooh!
[grunts]
哦！
[咕哝]
I'm still not
setting foot in here.
我还是没有
踏足这里。
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
Oh, that must be
the pizza I ordered!
哦，那一定是
我点的披萨！
[doorbell ringing]
[门铃响]
Whoop!
哎哟！
Pizza delivery.
披萨外送。
I'm not allowed
to open the door.
我不被允许
打开门。
Just slide the pizza
through the mail slot.
只需滑动披萨即可
通过邮件槽。
[pizza squishing, gurgling]
[披萨压扁，咕噜声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
And this is for you.
这是给你的。
My third
mail slot delivery tonight.
我的第三个
今晚邮件槽投递。
Must be a full moon.
一定是满月。
[slurping]
[发出声音]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[sighs]
[叹气]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[clears throat]
[清嗓子]
I'm here for the Fast Food
Founding Fathers Convention.
我是来吃快餐的
开国元勋大会。
Oh, you mean FFFF.
哦，你是说FFFF。
That'll be 10¢ entrance fee.
那将是 10 美分的入场费。
[shrieks]
[尖叫声]
10¢?
10美分？
That's a rip-off!
这就是敲诈勒索！
I'm going home!
我要回家了！
♪ ♪
♪♪
What kind of crazy convention
charges 10¢
什么样的疯狂大会
收费10美分
to a Founding... [stammers]
到一个建国之初...[结巴]
Congratulations, you're our
100th person to enter!
恭喜你，你是我们的
第100位入场！
Here's $1,000!
这是 1,000 美元！
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
What?
[holding note]
什么？
[持有笔记]
[static crackling]
[静电噼啪声]
[mellow music]
[柔和的音乐]
[lively music]
[活泼的音乐]
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
[chicken clucking]
- [munching]
[鸡咯咯叫]
- [咀嚼]
Shocking Cinema now returns
震撼影院现已回归
with tonight's
frightening feature:
与今晚的
可怕的功能：
"Knock, Knock, You're Dead."
“敲，敲，你死定了。”
[cackling]
[咯咯笑]
[shrieks]
[尖叫声]
I can't watch this!
[grunts]
我看不了这个！
[咕哝]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[knocking on door]
[敲门]
[shrieks, babbling]
[尖叫声、胡言乱语]
SpongeBob, open up!
海绵宝宝，打开吧！
I forgot me keys!
[groans]
我忘记带钥匙了！
[呻吟]
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
Huh?
SpongeBob?
啊？
海绵宝宝？
[sniffs, smacks lips]
[吸气，咂嘴]
What I always suspected:
我一直怀疑的是：
SpongeBob is made out of cheese!
海绵宝宝是用奶酪做的！
Hmm?
唔？
Or was made out of cheese.
或者是用奶酪制成的。
Oh...
- Who is it?
哦...
- 是谁？
It's me, Mr. Krabs!
Open up, boy!
是我，蟹老板！
打开吧，孩子！
You can't be Mr. Krabs.
你不可能是蟹老板。
Mr. Krabs is at a convention,
and he said
蟹老板正在参加一个会议，
他说
not to open the door for anyone.
不为任何人开门。
What?
[stammering furiously]
什么？
[愤怒地结巴]
Open up!
打开！
Oh, you sound
like Mr. Krabs, robber,
哦，你听起来
就像螃蟹先生，强盗，
but you look nothing like him!
但你看起来一点也不像他！
Hmm?
Barnacles!
唔？
藤壶！
Open up, you...
[stammering, grunting]
敞开心扉，你...
[结巴，咕哝]
Huh. Aha!
呵呵。啊哈！
[laughs, grunting]
[大笑，咕哝]
[devious music]
[狡猾的音乐]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[growls]
Hmm?
[咆哮]
嗯？
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ugh, and I told him
to check the windows, didn't I?
呃，我告诉他
检查窗户，不是吗？
[muttering unintelligibly]
[无法理解的咕哝]
Patrick, you've gotta
come over to Mr. Krabs' place!
帕特里克，你必须
到蟹老板那里来吧！
Someone's trying to break in! - [moans]
有人试图闯入！ -[呻吟]
Uh, SquarePants. - [moaning]
呃，方裤。 -[呻吟]
SpongeBob SquarePants. - [moans]
海绵宝宝。 -[呻吟]
No, you're Patrick!
不，你是帕特里克！
Please, hurry.
请快点。
[grunting]
Huh?
[咕噜声]
啊？
Patrick?
帕特里克？
What's that pink clown
doing here?
那个粉红色的小丑是什么
在这里做什么？
Eh, who cares?
呃，谁在乎呢？
SpongeBob will never open
the door for him.
海绵宝宝永远不会打开
为他开门。
[goofy babbling]
[胡言乱语]
Beep, beep, beep, beep.
嘟嘟嘟，嘟嘟嘟，嘟嘟嘟。
Great horn spoon!
很棒的牛角勺！
How's he doing that?
他怎么样？
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
[both holler, grunt]
[两者都喊叫，咕噜声]
[goofy exclamation, laughs]
[愚蠢的感叹，大笑]
Thank goodness you don't
have any bones, buddy.
谢天谢地你没有
有骨头吗，伙计。
Nope, all blubber.
不，全是胡言乱语。
[laughing]
[笑]
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
[gasps] Someone is trying
to break into Mr. Krabs' house.
[喘气]有人在尝试
闯入蟹老板的房子。
Then we'd better
get over there right away!
那我们最好
马上过去！
We're already here.
我们已经到了。
You mean you had me
walk in the rain for nothing?
你的意思是你拥有了我
雨中行走无缘无故？
[grunting]
I've got it...
[咕噜声]
我已经拿到了...
[grunting]
One little bit... there we go.
[咕噜声]
一点点……我们开始吧。
Huh?
[babbling]
啊？
[胡说]
[hollering]
[喊叫]
[groans]
[呻吟]
That robber doesn't
sound like he's gonna give up.
那个强盗不
听起来他要放弃了。
Let's set some traps.
让我们设置一些陷阱。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Check it out, Patrick:
看看吧，帕特里克：
if a robber happens
to open this door... bam!
如果发生强盗
打开这扇门...砰！
This pillow will fall
on their head.
这个枕头会掉下来
在他们的头上。
I call it "soft justice."
我称之为“软正义”。
Good one.[laughs]
不错啊[笑]
Look at mine!
看看我的！
If a robber tries to come in
through the window,
如果强盗试图闯入
透过窗户，
they'll put their hand
in this warm water
他们会把手伸过来
在这温热的水中
and they'll have to run
to the bathroom!
他们必须跑
去卫生间！
[laughing]
[笑]
House all secure.
Now we relax.
房子一切安全。
现在我们放松一下。
[glass shatters]
[玻璃碎裂]
The robber!
To the battle stations!
强盗！
前往战斗站！
[grunting]
There we go.
[咕噜声]
我们开始吧。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[wails]
Midnight Pincer?
[哀号]
午夜钳子？
It smells so wonderful,
闻起来真是美妙极了
but it burns!
但它会燃烧！
[wails, grunts]
[哀号，咕噜声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Take that![grunts]
拿着那个！[咕哝]
Desperate times
call for desperate measures.
绝望的时刻
呼吁采取绝望的措施。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
What the... not on my watch!
什么……不在我的监视之下！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[babbling]
[胡说]
[laughs]
The pet door.
[笑]
宠物门。
Why didn't I think
of this before?
为什么我没想到
以前有过这个吗？
Oh, boy.
[laughs]
哦，男孩。
[笑]
Huh?
[shrieks]
啊？
[尖叫声]
Hmm.
唔。
Hmm, cheddar.
嗯，切达干酪。
Sharp cheddar.
锋利的切达干酪。
[cow moos]
[牛哞哞]
[growling]
That's it!
[咆哮]
就是这样！
Time to wreck this ball.
是时候毁掉这个球了。
No Mr. Krabs-impersonating
robber will ever get
禁止冒充蟹老板
强盗将永远得到
into this house
with us on the job.
进入这所房子
与我们一起工作。
We're tough guys.
- Yeah.
我们是硬汉。
- 是的。
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
Uh, I feel like
a tough guy action movie.
呃，我感觉
一部硬汉动作片。
Oh, the tougher
the better, buddy!
哦，越艰难
越好，伙计！
Oh, yeah! - [grunts]
哦，是啊！ -[咕哝]
[banging]
[砰砰]
Wow, Mr. Krabs sure has
an awesome TV noise machine!
哇，蟹老板确实有
很棒的电视噪音机！
[banging]
[砰砰]
[growling]
[咆哮]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[thunder crashing]
[雷霆轰鸣]
[grunts]
I'm coming in hot!
[咕哝]
我火热来啦！
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
both: Wow, 3-D!
两人：哇，3D！
[groans]
[呻吟]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[grunts, groans]
[咕哝声，呻吟声]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
[melancholy music]
[忧郁的音乐]
I give up.
我放弃。
Here, look,
在这里，看，
this proves
I'm the real Mr. Krabs.
这证明
我才是真正的蟹老板。
both: Hmm...
hmm...
两人：嗯……
嗯...
Oh...
[laughs]
哦...
[笑]
Says you're an organ donor.
说你是器官捐献者。
Nice.
- You play the organ?
好的。
- 你弹风琴吗？
Give me that.
both: Sorry, Mr. Krabs.
给我那个。
两人：对不起，蟹老板。
Oh, it's all right.
哦，没关系。
I can't be mad at you
for following me orders.
我不能生你的气
听从我的命令。
You did good, boyo.
你做得很好，男孩。
You, too, Pat-o.
[both laugh]
你也是，帕特奥。
[两人都笑了]
[knocking on door]
[敲门]
all: Huh?
- The robber.
全体：啊？
- 强盗。
Daddy, open up, it's Pearl!
爸爸，开门，是珍珠！
I forgot my keys!
- [grunts]
我忘记带钥匙了！
- [咕哝]
Well, you sound
like me daughter,
嗯，你听起来
像我女儿一样，
Mr. Robber,
强盗先生，
but you look nothing like her!
但你看起来一点都不像她！
[laughs]
[both exclaim]
[笑]
[两人惊呼]
Hmm?
唔？
Hmm.
唔。
Are those me private things?
那些是我的私事吗？
Daddy!
[whines]
爸爸！
[哀鸣]
Daddy!
爸爸！